okay so here are the slides so this is
好吧，这是幻灯片，这是
what I was saying is this is the thing
我说的就是这个
that we wanted we want to gun up your
我们想要我们想炮制您的
right coat and and here are the two
正确的外套，这是两个
games that I just want you now what I
我现在只想要你的游戏
really want to present is Rx and not
真的想呈现的是Rx而不是
kind of you know if you really want to
你知道你是否真的想
write full games there's a lot of things
写完整的游戏有很多事情
that are very gauge specific so I've
这是非常规范的，所以我已经
kept the game super simple to highlight
保持游戏超级简单突出
the re aspects and if we look at the
有关方面，如果我们看看
source code of the games you saw them in
您在其中看到的游戏的源代码
Ellijay and a second ago
Ellijay和一秒钟前
but the source code of these games
但是这些游戏的源代码
really is like at most two screens full
真的好像最多两个屏幕都满了
of code so and the snake and the book
这样的代码以及蛇和书
you see the snake has a little bit
你看到蛇有一点
longer lines but it's all super simple
更长的线条，但是一切都超级简单
code and so even you know my
代码，所以即使你知道我的
six-year-old son is able to write games
六岁的儿子能够写游戏
like this using rx and he is having a
像这样使用RX，他有一个
lot of fun with it now in order to
为了给它带来很多乐趣
present rx I want to first talk a little
现在的RX我想先谈一点
bit about programming using M
关于使用M编程的一点知识
collections or in the new speak of Java
集合或Java的新说法
programming with streams because if you
使用流进行编程，因为如果您
look at at this game it reacts to the
看这个游戏，它对
keyboard and the mouse which are
键盘和鼠标是
sequences of things and it transforms
事物的序列及其变化
them into other sequences namely update
将它们分为其他顺序即更新
to the screen so really a game as I
到屏幕上，就像我一样真正的游戏
present it today can be seen as a
今天提出的可以看作是
transformation from streams to other
从流向其他的转化
streams and then you know these the
流，然后你知道这些
resulting streams are rendered on the on
产生的流在
the screen so the first thing in order
屏幕，所以第一件事
to understand Rx is that we have to
要了解Rx，我们必须
understand very deeply what streams up
非常深刻地了解什么流
so if we go and look at Java there we
所以如果我们去那里看看Java
see that there's a day
看到有一天
interface here that you see it there are
在这里看到它的界面
many many types that implement that
许多实现该目标的类型
interface and that interface is called
接口，该接口称为
interval interval of E and I call it the
E的间隔间隔，我称之为
mother of all streams now in Java 8 and
Java 8和
the mother of all streams has been
所有流的母亲一直
replaced by a new interface and that
换成新介面，
interface is called stream of T and now
接口称为T流，现在
this interface stream of T is actually
T的这个接口流实际上是
quite interesting so let's take a short
非常有趣，让我们花点时间
look at it so if you look at the Java 8
看看它，所以如果您看一下Java 8
documentation stream of T is defined as
T的文档流定义为
follows us dream of T and it has super
跟随我们T的梦想
interfaces and this is interesting it
接口，这很有趣
inherits from a stream of T and stream
继承自T和stream的流
of T and if we look at bay stream of T
T，如果我们看一下T的湾流
then we see that that's a generic type
然后我们看到那是一个通用类型
that has two parameters where the second
有两个参数，第二个
parameter is restricted to an extent
参数在一定程度上受到限制
based stream of T and s again now I
现在基于T和s的流
don't know about you but at this point
不了解你，但在这一点上
my brain stack is over flown and because
我的脑袋飞满了，因为
if you would unfold this type you would
如果您展开此类型，您将
see that it ends up into in base stream
看到它最终进入基本流
of base stream of base stream of base 3
基本3的基本流的基本流
of T so and it goes all the way down now
大约是T，现在一直下降
I don't know about you but compared to
我不认识你，但与
this everything that we're doing today
这就是我们今天要做的一切
will be too real ok so don't worry you
太真实了，所以不要担心你
know you can handle Java 8 and you can
知道您可以处理Java 8并且可以
handle types like stream of T and which
处理T之类的类型以及
every jabber programmer is supposed to
每个jabber程序员都应该
understand you have no problem with rx
了解您对rx没问题
now when I said that stream replaced
现在，当我说那条小溪取代了
interval of T I think there's a little
TI的间隔认为有一点
bit of a denial in Java 8 because if you
Java 8中的一点拒绝，因为如果您
look at the methods of base stream you
看一下基本流的方法
see that
看到
has an iterator and method that returns
有一个返回的迭代器和方法
an iterator so really a base stream is
一个迭代器，所以实际上是基本流
an interval except that in Java 8 and
一个间隔，除了Java 8和
it's not mentioned like like that but
不是像那样被提及
it's really and the case so I think Java
确实如此，所以我认为Java
8 is in denial that it really supports
8否认它确实支持
the mother of all connections and now
所有联系的母亲，现在
why is Java 8 have streams well it is
为什么Java 8拥有良好的流
because we want to do bulk operations on
因为我们要对
these collections so here's the example
这些集合，所以这是例子
taken from the Java 8 documentation so
取自Java 8文档，因此
what it does is it says given some
它的作用是说给定一些
collection of widgets convert it to a
小部件集合将其转换为
stream that's I'm done with this first
流，这是我首先完成的
call and then we filter out all the
呼叫，然后我们过滤掉所有
widgets that are red and then you know
红色的小部件，然后您知道
we map all the widgets to their weight
我们将所有小部件映射到它们的权重
and then we sum the result so here you
然后我们对结果求和，所以在这里
see the kind of typical transformation
看到那种典型的转变
of collections to other collections
集合到其他集合
using filtering folding mapping
使用过滤折叠映射
aggregating and whatever you want but I
聚集，无论您想要什么，但我
want to point out one interesting
想指出一个有趣的地方
philosophical remark in the Java 8
Java 8中的哲学评论
documentation and that is that the
文档，那就是
distinction they make between streams
他们区分流
and collections is that strings don't
而且收集是字符串不
provide a way to access and manipulate
提供访问和操纵的方式
elements of the stream of the collection
集合流的元素
and what that means is that if you look
这意味着如果你看
at collections like hash tables and
在像哈希表和
arrays lists and so on these all have
数组列表等等，这些都有
operations where you can directly index
您可以直接索引的操作
into the collection and then mutate the
进入集合，然后将
values whereas with a stream the only
值，而只有流
thing you can do is you can enumerate
你可以做的事就是你可以列举
the values and you can do
价值观，你可以做
something with it and you can generate a
用它可以产生一个
new and connection so that's a very
新的和连接，所以这是一个非常
important distinction that is mentioned
提到的重要区别
here and you know between the lines but
在这里，你知道线之间，但
it's really and I think significant vais
是的，我认为很重要
a big change from the old world where we
与旧世界相比发生了很大的变化
would do imperative mutations on
会对命令式进行突变
collections to a new world to a more
集合到新世界，再到更多
functional programming oriented work
面向函数式编程的工作
world where we're just going to be know
我们将要知道的世界
doing operations on collections to
对集合进行操作
create new collections ok so here is one
创建新收藏好，这是一个
of the operations that we did here in
我们在这里所做的操作
this little example filter and if you
这个小例子过滤器，如果你
draw the picture of filter what you see
画出您所看到的滤镜图片
is that it takes a collection that's up
是它需要一个收集
here so here we have a collection and
在这里，这里我们有一个收藏
then we filter out all the values that
然后我们过滤掉所有的值
are in circles and what you see is that
在圈子里，你看到的是
you know there's a new collection that
你知道有一个新的收藏
now only contains circles and again it
现在只包含圈子，再一次
doesn't really matter what's the
没什么关系
underlying I should have called this is
我应该称其为基础的是
stream of course and because it really
当然，因为它真的
doesn't matter what the underlying
无关紧要的是什么
collection is this could be a hash table
集合是一个哈希表
or a list but the only thing that we
或列表，但我们唯一
care about is that we take the values of
我们关心的是
the underlying collection presented as a
基础集合表示为
stream and then filter out the older
流，然后过滤掉较旧的
circles and then we get a new stream
圈子，然后我们得到了一个新的流
that only contains circles and then we
只包含圆圈，然后我们
can add other operations to that so
可以为此添加其他操作
really stream programming is about both
真正的流编程既涉及
transformations on dreams of values and
价值梦想的转变和
if you know sequel that's kind of
如果你知道续集的话
something that the database people have
数据库人员拥有的东西
been doing since the early 70s here's
自70年代初开始就在这里
another operation
另一个操作
um and dreams and methane so mapping and
嗯，梦想和甲烷，所以绘制
takes a stream in this case a stream of
在这种情况下需要一个流
circles and then it generates another
圆圈，然后生成另一个
stream and in this case a stream of
流，在这种情况下是
diamonds and the way it does that is by
钻石及其操作方式是
taking a function that turns a circle
采取转圈的功能
into a diamond and this is here where
成钻石，这是这里
you see the the different no programming
你看到不同的没有编程
nature of stream for programming and
流的性质，用于编程和
comes in is in order to transfer one
进来是为了转移一个
string to another you have to pass in a
字符串到另一个，你必须传递一个
function that works on each element so
对每个元素起作用的功能
you specify how to change
您指定如何更改
Terkel into a diamond and then you make
泰克尔变成钻石，然后你做
that one function over three to
那一个功能超过三
transform it into another stream in the
将其转换为另一个流
little example we also saw the operation
小例子，我们也看到了操作
with some and some takes a stream of
有一些需要一些
values of numbers and then returns a
数字值，然后返回
string or value and that contains this
字符串或值，并且包含此内容
the value that represents the sum of the
代表
stream now it's a question you know how
现在流，这是一个问题，你知道如何
do you represent the result of an
你代表一个结果吗
operation like some and aggregate like
像一些操作和聚合一样
some and and if you look here in the
一些，如果你在这里看
original example you see that some
原来的例子，你看到一些
returns an integer but that's really not
返回一个整数，但实际上不是
the only possible choice if you take a
唯一可能的选择
more database oriented view there when
何时有更多面向数据库的视图
you do an aggregate a collection is
你做一个集合的集合是
reduced to another collection that that
减少到另一个收藏
contains just a single element which is
仅包含一个元素
the aggregate of that collection and it
该集合及其的汇总
really that that kind of price really
那种价格真的
doesn't matter so we will be a little
没关系，所以我们会有点
bit think about that but here again you
稍微想一下，但再次在这里
see this picture and it doesn't really
看到这张照片，它不是真的
matter again where this three
再有问题，这三个
originates from the only thing that we
源自我们唯一的事物
do is we say we want to sum all the
是说我们要对所有
elements and then in the end we get
元素，最后我们得到
a single element that is the sum of all
一个元素，是所有元素的总和
elements in the original stream and
原始流中的元素和
that's really the most important message
这确实是最重要的信息
of today is we have to start thinking in
今天是我们必须开始思考
terms of streams so those are just you
流的术语，所以那些就是你
know sequences of values where you
知道你在哪里值序列
cannot you know access any underlying
你不知道访问任何底层
data structure the only thing you can do
数据结构唯一可以做的
is you get D values and somehow one by
是D值吗？
one you don't even know and and then you
一个你甚至不认识的人，然后你
transform these streams into other
将这些流转化为其他流
streams by passing in higher-order
通过高阶流
functions and when I set that you don't
功能，当我设置为不
even know that you get these values one
甚至知道你得到这些价值观之一
by one is because if you do the map like
一个是因为如果您像
what we saw here and the underlying
我们在这里看到的以及潜在的
limitation of map actually might run
地图的限制实际上可能会运行
many of the map functions that you pass
您传递的许多Map函数
in here in parallel if you if you have
如果有的话，在这里并行
heard of Hadoop or MapReduce that's
听说过Hadoop或MapReduce
exactly what happens there is it uses
到底发生了什么事
this abstraction of bulk processing over
大量处理的抽象
streams to effectively implement that on
流以有效地实现
a large cluster of machines and the
一大堆机器和
trick again is that you abstract away
再次把戏是你抽象了
and of any properties of the Lurline
和Lurline的任何特性
collections because if you assume that
集合，因为如果您假设
you can index into an array well you
你可以很好地索引到数组中
have bad luck when you have to and
运气不好的时候
distribute that array over cluster of
将该阵列分布在
machines and index it will definitely
机器和索引肯定会
not be constant time anymore
不再是固定的时间
okay so it's really by limiting
好的，所以实际上是通过限制
ourselves to to a simpler interface the
自己到一个更简单的界面
iterable interface or stream interface
可迭代接口或流接口
in this case that you get more power and
在这种情况下，您将获得更多动力，
that's often the case in programming by
在编程中通常是这样
making less assumptions we can do much
减少假设，我们可以做很多事情
more so in some sense we're going back
从某种意义上讲，我们要回去
to basics so throw away all these
基本的东西，所以扔掉所有这些
Baroque Asia structures with all kind of
巴洛克式的亚洲结构与各种
special case and efficient operations we
特例和高效运营
if we go to get efficiency in a
如果我们去提高效率
different way we to throw away many many
我们抛弃许多许多不同的方式
operations and work with super simple
操作和工作超级简单
data structures or streams now and there
到处都是数据结构或流
isn't really much new order some because
并不是真正的新订单，因为
if you look at what mathematicians have
如果你看看数学家有什么
done and they have been working with
完成，他们一直在与
sets or collections for a long time and
设置或收集很长时间
one of the fundamental theorems in our
我们的基本定理之一
axioms in ethics is the axiom of choice
道德公理是选择的公理
and one way to look at the axiom of
一种看待公理的方法
choice to say that mathematical sets are
选择说数学集是
iterable so it's really but you know
迭代，所以它是真的，但是你知道
we're just following in the footsteps of
我们只是在跟随
you know super smart people like you
你知道像你这样的超级聪明人
know fairly nonce or Melo here on the
在这里知道相当随机数或Melo
picture and just to remind you here's
图片，只是为了提醒您
the interface for interval again it has
接口再次具有间隔
one method iterator which gives you an
一种方法迭代器
iterator and that one has the choice
迭代器，并且可以选择
function as you know it's airmail we'd
就像您知道的航空邮件一样
say and that is the next function so you
说，那是下一个功能，所以你
can kind of repeatedly ask for the next
可以反复要求下一个
function the next value in this stream
在此流中作用下一个值
and that's all you can do with a string
这就是字符串所能做的一切
so again by restricting ourselves to a
因此，再次将自己限制为
super simple interface certainly we can
超级简单的界面，当然我们可以
do amazing things and by combining
做奇妙的事情，并结合
higher-order functions over such simple
如此简单的高阶函数
collections now one of the powerful
现在是功能强大的收藏之一
things of a stream or in this case an
流或在这种情况下
interval is that there doesn't has to be
间隔是没有必要
have to be a underlying collection that
必须是一个基础集合
backs up the interval and for example
备份间隔，例如
here I'm creating
我在这里创建
simple program to generate a stream of
生成流的简单程序
random numbers do you see here so I'm
你在这里看到随机数，所以我
creating a stream of random numbers and
创建一个随机数流
then I'm printing them out and I'm
然后我将它们打印出来，
implementing this using interval but you
实现这个使用间隔，但是你
see there is no collection there's just
看到没有收藏，只有
like a one piece of state which is this
就像这是一个状态
random number generator and and for the
随机数生成器和
rest there is no collection okay this
休息那里没有收藏好吗
tree the elements of stream only exist
树中流元素仅存在
at the moment that you ask the next
当你问下一个
element and then they're gone so if we
元素，然后它们消失了，如果我们
take a more philosophical approach to
采取更哲学的方法
streams it's really that when you're
流是真的，当你
doing programming you have to focus on
做编程时你必须专注于
the present you have to focus on now
现在你现在必须集中精力
there is no past there is no future
没有过去就没有未来
the only thing that you can hold in your
唯一可以保留在自己的东西
hands is the current element of the
手是当前的元素
stream and that is precisely what's the
流，这正是
iterable interface gives you you have
可迭代的界面让您拥有
the current value and that's it you
当前值就是这样
don't know whether this an interval
不知道这是否有间隔
you know remembers the past and you have
你知道记得过去，你拥有
no way to know what the future is of an
无法知道未来的发展
interval the only thing you can assume
间隔，你可以假设的唯一
is the present and and so that's going
是现在，所以这将会
to do the mindset that we have to get in
做我们必须进入的心态
good now that we have seen a couple of
现在好了，我们已经看到了几个
streams we have been lobed philosophical
流我们已经被哲学抛弃
about streams let's start to look for
关于流，让我们开始寻找
streams everywhere and so here is a
流无处不在，所以这是一个
stream and when I move my mouse I get
流，当我移动鼠标时，我得到
the stream of mouse positions and again
鼠标位置流
there is the mouse is always at the
有鼠标总是在
single position and the mouse doesn't
单位置，鼠标不
remember where it was
记得在哪里
five positions ago and the mouse doesn't
五个位置之前，鼠标没有
know where it will be you know five
知道会在哪里，你知道五个
seconds from now the only thing that the
从现在起的几秒钟内
mouse knows is that it is the current
鼠标知道这是当前的
position right now
现在的位置
let's look at another stream and it's
让我们看看另一个流，它是
this stream of of stock prices and there
这种股票价格流
is a current stock price and you know
是当前的股价，你知道
there might be a history of the stock
可能有库存历史
price but you have to explicitly keep
价格，但您必须明确保持
that but you definitely don't know what
那，但是你绝对不知道
the future will be off of a stock symbol
未来将摆脱股票符号
okay so again the only thing you can
好吧，那么唯一可以做的就是
really do is to kind of focus on the now
真正要做的是有点专注于现在
what is the current stock price and then
当前的股价是多少，然后
you will be told what is the next one
您将被告知下一个是什么
but you have to kind of you know the
但您必须知道
only thing you have in your hand is the
您手中只有的是
current stock price now for you and that
您现在的当前股价
have children you will be super familiar
有孩子，你会超级熟悉
and with another stream a stream of
与另一股流
screams and they're also and there's no
尖叫，他们也是，没有
way that you know and you can control
您知道并可以控制的方式
your baby and it will scream and it will
你的宝宝，它会尖叫，它会
kind of just and send out a stream of
有点公正，并发出一连串的
screams when the baby is not happy
婴儿不开心时尖叫
alright so again it's like one of these
好吧，再次像其中之一
streams that has like a current state
具有当前状态的流
and with babies then the next second
和婴儿，然后下一秒钟
they suddenly might smile and then they
他们突然可能会微笑，然后他们
start crying again it's very hard to get
再哭一次，很难
you know predict how they will behave so
你知道预测他们的行为方式
um we have seen two very different kinds
嗯，我们已经看到了两种截然不同的类型
of streams the one string the first
流的第一个字符串
stream the iterable streams were dreams
溪流是梦
where you only get a value when you ask
当你问的时候你只会获得价值
for it and and that's like a pumpjack
为此，这就像一个抽水机
where you're going to pumping for oil
你要去抽油的地方
only when you're kind of pumping you get
只有当你抽水时，你才能得到
some oil and and then the second kind of
一些油，然后第二种
streams that we saw were streams that
我们看到的流是
would give you values whether you want
是否会给您价值
it or not whether you can handle them or
是否可以处理它们
not they will just kind of blow up
他们不会只是炸毁
notifying you that something
通知你某事
has happened so let's look at the
已经发生了，所以让我们看一下
interface the second kind of stream and
接口第二种流，并
we call those observable streams and
我们称这些可观察的流
nocturnal streams are the core of our X
夜间流是我们X的核心
so what are observable streams well they
所以什么是可观察的流
are also out of two interfaces so the
也在两个接口之外，所以
first one is observable of T which has
第一个是可观察到的T
one method subscribe to which you give
一种您订阅的方法
an observer and then an observer is
一个观察者，然后一个观察者是
really three callbacks that will be
真的三个回调将是
called whenever something happens in the
每当事件发生时调用
underlying implementation of the
基础实施
observable so an inspector here is that
可观察到的，所以这里的检查员是
you know you give a an event handler to
你知道你给一个事件处理程序
this thing and whenever there's an
这个东西，只要有
interesting and event occurring your
有趣的事件发生
callback will be called whether you can
是否可以调用回调
handle it or not whether you want it but
是否要处理它，但是
once you've registered the callback to
将回调注册到
an observable collection you will be
一个可观察的集合
pulled just like with your baby
就像婴儿一样被拉
once you have baby it will be it will
一旦你有了孩子，它将是
call you and at any time it doesn't
打电话给你，任何时候都不会
matter whether it's day or night whether
不管是白天还是晚上
you are sleep you have to know it okay
你在睡觉，你必须知道
now let's say show some code again here
现在让我们说再次在这里显示一些代码
is an example of the same stream of
是同一流的一个例子
random numbers now as an observable so
现在可以观察到随机数
what you see here again I just have a
你再次在这里看到的，我只有一个
single piece of state random and then I
单件状态随机然后我
just keep pushing out a random numbers
只是不断推出一个随机数
and then here I take the first five and
然后在这里我拿前五个
print them out so you see this is
打印出来，所以你看到这是
behaves kind of the same as the original
表现与原始影片相同
iterable stream that I made random
我随机创建的可迭代流
numbers except that in this case you
数字，但在这种情况下，您
don't ask for the values but yet deliver
不要求值，但要交付
and at you good and again on these
在你身上又一次在这些
streams doesn't matter we can do the
流无关紧要，我们可以做到
same bulk operations like map filter
相同的批量操作，例如地图过滤器
fault
故障
etc so you filter again you see and let
等等，所以你再次过滤，你看到并让
me re-emphasize it this thing if the
我重新强调这件事，如果
stream of values comes flying by you
价值之流在你身边飞扬
you can filter out all the circles and
您可以过滤掉所有圈子，
then you get a new stream and that will
然后你会得到一个新的流，这将
fly by the next operation on the up
在下一个操作上飞
streams the same format if you see a
如果看到
stratum of and circles fly by in the
和的层在
function to convert circles into
将圈子转换成
diamonds you get a new stream that
钻石，您会获得新的流
contains only diamonds good so now and
只包含优质钻石，所以现在和
we're getting closer to the actual game
我们正在接近实际游戏
and and the other thing that I want to
还有我想要的另一件事
go and talk about is optimal collections
去谈论是最佳收藏
if you are a Java programmer and you
如果您是Java程序员，而您
have used jar of X for example you will
例如用过X罐子
have noticed that there people talk
注意到那里有人在说话
about observed both elections if you are
关于观察两次选举，如果你是
a dotnet programmer and you're using
一个dotnet程序员，您正在使用
Zemel or some work like that you will
Zemel或类似的工作，您将
also hear people talk about observable
也听到人们谈论可观察的
collections in JavaScript there are
JavaScript中的集合有
hundreds of data binding framework
数百种数据绑定框架
frameworks that all have observable
都有可观察的框架
collections and notifications and so on
集合和通知等
so what is the relationship between the
那两者之间是什么关系
RX observables and these observable
RX可观察物和这些可观察物
collections and well the connection is
集合，以及连接是
actually quite close and here is the
其实很近，这是
picture so if you look at this picture
图片，所以如果你看这张图片
here you see that the observable
在这里，您可以看到
collection is a concrete collection in
收藏是一个具体的收藏
the sense of Java eight so it's not a
Java 8的意义，所以它不是
stream it's a collection it has a set of
流这是一个集合，它具有一组
operators on it in particular you can
特别是它上的运算符
mutate these observable collections and
改变这些可观察的集合，并
whenever the Mutai
每当木台
them you will be notified of a change
他们将通知您更改
right sir this is your observable
对，先生，这是你的观察
collections these are three specific
这些是三个特定的集合
data structures that have mutating
具有变异的数据结构
operations defined on them and whenever
在它们以及任何时候定义的操作
you do the mutation on the observable
你在可观察的地方做突变
collection it will notify you and of the
收藏它将通知您和
change so that's the kind of direct
变化，这就是直接
connection between our X observables and
我们的X观测值与
observable collections now typically you
现在可以观察到的收藏集
can also kind of take a look at the
也可以看一下
actual values of an observable
可观察的实际值
collections extreme or as an interval
极端或间隔收集
and by just going to enumerate in them
并通过列举它们来
whereas the observable part is really
而可观察的部分是
about notifying you of changes okay airp
关于通知您更改，好吧airp
yes hi connect can we just ask two
是的，嗨，我们可以问两个吗
questions because I think both have it
问题，因为我认为两者都有
um yet one of them is such asks do you
嗯，其中之一就是这样问你
have a mechanism wearing you can persist
有机制可以坚持
the stream of values so that we can
价值流，以便我们可以
reply in case for example the subscriber
回复例如订户
is down and yes most definitely so let
倒了，是的，绝对可以，所以让
me again appear as see if I can and get
我再次出现，看我是否可以得到
this to work if you get me second
如果你让我第二，这可以工作
because my screen list and you see this
因为我的屏幕列表，您看到了
we see the paper show okay good so and
我们看到纸张显示还可以，所以
let's kind of try to enter discretion to
让我们尝试输入酌处权
say that we have a stream of values like
说我们有一系列价值
this and I call this they can't marble
这个，我称他们不能弹大理石
diagrams and and now and this is time
图，现在，这是时间
now as I said if you look at this thing
现在就像我说的，如果你看这件事
as a stream if time is here all the
作为流，如果时间在这里
values that happens before here will be
在此之前发生的值将是
lost because you know that the time just
迷失了，因为你知道时间
marches on and so there will be next
继续前进，所以接下来会有
values and if you join the stream here
值，如果您在此处加入信息流
you won't see any of the values here
您将在此处看不到任何值
course there are other operators where
当然还有其他运营商
you know what you can do is that you can
你知道你能做的就是
remember those values and now when you
记住那些价值观，现在当你
would join the stream here it will give
将在这里加入流，它将给
you these three values that happened in
您发生的这三个价值
the past and then you will continue
过去，然后你会继续
receiving and the new values so this
接收和新值，这样
thing in our access code the replay
接入码中的内容重播
subject and that's a special operator
主题，这是一个特殊的运算符
that you can apply to a stream that will
您可以将其应用于将
remember the values that happened in the
记住发生在
past but what you can see here already
过去，但您已经可以在这里看到
now is that you know the longer you wait
现在，您知道等待的时间更长
so the more values have appeared over
所以更多的价值出现了
time the more values that you have to
时间，您必须拥有更多的价值
kind of remember in here so that's in
记得在这里，所以在
some sense a dangerous operation because
有些人认为这是危险的操作，因为
this represents a memory so we have you
这代表着回忆，所以我们有你
when you create a replace object you can
创建替换对象时，您可以
have a count here you say you know I
伯爵在这里你说你知道我
only want to remember the last end
只想记住最后的结局
values or you have a time thing here
价值观，或者你在这里有时间
where you can say you want to kind of
在这里你可以说你想
only remember the values from a certain
只记得某个特定的值
period I hope that that answers the
期间我希望能回答
question yeah um so I think the second
是的，嗯，我想第二个
one is kind of related which you
一种是与您相关的
probably already answered which is the
可能已经回答了
question was what would happen if events
问题是如果发生事件会怎样
are generated more rapidly that
产生得更快
observers can handle so I think you kind
观察员可以应付，所以我认为你很友善
of covered that okay so that is that is
的覆盖那好吧，那就是
a question that is how should I say that
我要说的是一个问题
requires a lot more time to explain and
需要更多时间来解释和
but if you look at the one extreme if
但是如果你看一个极端的话
you really look at going to do an normal
你真的看着去做一个正常的
event system there you have to always
那里的事件系统你必须总是
able to and handle things that are
能够处理
thrown at you and for example let me
扔给你，例如让我
kind of give you
有点给你
in an example and say that you're
在一个例子中，说你是
writing a stock trading application and
编写股票交易申请，以及
you know you for some reason you're just
你因为某种原因认识你
an amateur
一个业余
so you write it in Visual Basic and and
所以你用Visual Basic和
yours your Visual Basic of course you
您的Visual Basic当然是您
know you can also write fast code in
知道您也可以在其中编写快速代码
Visual Basic I should not make fun of
我不应取笑的Visual Basic
Visual Basic and work on visual basic
Visual Basic和Visual Basic上的工作
but just you know as an example and say
但以您所知为例
that your application can only handle
您的应用程序只能处理
hundreds transactions per hour and now
每小时数百笔交易，现在
you're not going to kind of tell the New
你不会告诉新的
York change hey hey hey you know my
纽约变化嘿嘿嘿你知道我的
software cannot handle you know a
软件无法处理您知道的
massive flow of transactions please slow
大量交易请放慢速度
down
下
and you will have to deal with it and on
您将不得不继续处理
the other extreme is the iterable
另一个极端是可迭代的
interface where you know if they're you
界面，您可以知道他们是否是您
only asked for values so it's really
只问值，所以它真的
kind you know it's like the no new value
你知道这就像没有新的价值
is is generated unless you ask for it
除非您要求，否则生成
and and the reason I say that this
我说这个的原因
question requires a lot more time to
问题需要更多时间
answer is that there's a whole design
答案是有一个整体设计
space in the middle where you know you
你知道你的中间的空间
might balance the kind of 1x3 where you
可能会平衡您所处的1x3
always have to handle the production of
总是要处理
values with something where you can of
值与您可以
kind of you have a hybrid model where
你们有一个混合模型
you can ask and you know so on but I
你可以问，你知道，但是我
always believe that you have to get that
一直相信你必须得到那个
the most and fruitful way to look at
最富有成效的方法
software is to look at the extremes and
软件要看极端
if you cannot handle the extremes you
如果您无法应对极端情况，
know then you don't even know what is in
知道那你甚至不知道里面有什么
the middle and but again there there's a
中间，但又有一个
whole kind of design space of interfaces
整个界面设计空间
for collections that are in the middle I
对于中间的收藏
hope that that answers the question and
希望能回答这个问题，
okay and I'm just I don't want to keep
好吧，我只是不想保留
up too much em no no god that's let's
太多了，不，没有上帝，让我们
ask the questions so - you know nothing
这么问问题-你什么都不知道
good for me with us okay um so the other
对我们有好处，好吧，所以其他
one is
一个是
do we have a prior to order that we
我们有事先订购的东西吗
could assign for the subscribers sorry
可以为订户分配抱歉
can you repeat that a what do we have a
您能重复一遍吗我们有什么
priority order that we could assign for
我们可以分配的优先顺序
the subscribers so basically if the
基本上，如果
subscribers can have priority set okay
订户可以设置优先级
so if you again that's it that's a very
所以如果你又是那是一个非常
good question so let me move this thing
好问题，让我移动这件事
and here for a second and move back to
再过一秒钟再回到
and the interface here so what you see
和这里的界面，您所看到的
here is that the the observable
这是可观察的
interface by itself only has a method
接口本身只有一个方法
where you can subscribe to it and so the
在哪里可以订阅它，所以
basic interface has no notion of
基本界面没有
priority for subscribers but that
订户的优先权，但这
doesn't mean that you know you cannot
并不意味着你知道你不能
have a sub type of observable that
有一个可观察到的子类型
allows you to have subscribers with
允许您订阅
different priorities again if you look
如果您再看一遍
at the collection class I won't kind of
在收藏课上，我不会
scroll all the way back but there are
一直滚动回来，但是有
like you know maybe like mandolin in the
就像你知道的那样
standard Java SDK there's probably 50
标准Java SDK可能有50个
concrete collections that implement
实现的具体集合
iterable
可迭代的
and so the same thing is with observable
所以同样的事情是可以观察到的
ya there if you won't have a special
你在那里，如果你没有特别
behavior like you know I want to
像你知道我想要的行为
distinguish between the different
区分不同
subscribers you would have to define a
订阅者，您必须定义一个
special observable that has these
具有这些的特殊可观察物
additional properties this is just a
其他属性，这只是一个
regular interface based design where you
基于常规界面的设计，您可以在其中
know you have like a main interface that
知道你像一个主界面
has the newest constraints and if you
具有最新的约束条件，如果您
need more constraints you add them by
需要更多的约束，您可以通过添加
subtyping and having a derived interface
子类型化并具有派生接口
that has more properties all right likes
拥有更多属性的就好
um yep so I think we can continue thanks
是的，我想我们可以继续感谢
good and now notice even this is
好，现在注意到，即使这是
interesting you know the interface for
有趣的是您知道界面
subscribers doesn't even kind of
订阅者甚至没有
mention that there's a list of
提到有一个清单
subscribers or anything right so the
订户或其他任何对的人，
only thing you can do is you can
你唯一能做的就是
subscribe and then you can get back this
订阅，然后您可以取回
subscription using which you can
订阅，您可以使用
unsubscribe so there are actually many
取消订阅，因此实际上有很多
many implementations of observables that
可观察对象的许多实现
don't maintain any list of subscribers
不维护任何订户列表
and and so that's why I'm having this
这就是为什么我要这个
something that has a priority for
优先考虑的事情
subscribers should not be in the base in
订户不应位于
face good filter map our observable
面对好的滤镜图我们可以观察到
collections so here we were so went
收集，所以我们在这里过得去
before we had the questions so the
在我们提出问题之前，
observable collections with the mutating
变异的可观察的集合
operations and whenever you mutate and
操作以及您进行突变和
you will be notified of the change so
您将收到更改通知，因此
again here you see is you know if
再次在这里，您是否知道
somebody is mutating the collection and
有人在改变集合，
you get notified no matter what I mean
无论我是什么意思，您都会收到通知
somebody else is mutating and if you
有人在变异，如果你
cannot keep up with the changes and bad
跟不上变化和坏处
luck for you now if you look at this
如果你看看这个，现在为你带来好运
this picture here you say hmm I know
这幅画在这里你说嗯我知道
I've seen this before and if you've done
我以前看过，如果你看过
the course on databases you will notice
您将注意到的数据库课程
that this is exactly what the database
这正是数据库
does it's you have a lock and then you
是不是你有一把锁，然后你
know every time you mutate the database
每次更改数据库时都知道
and new entry is added to the lock and
并将新条目添加到锁中，
the current state of the database is
数据库的当前状态是
just a of the lock records and that's
只是一个锁记录，那是
the same here if you look here if I
如果我在这里看，我也一样
would replay all changes I can always
会重播所有我可以随时更改的内容
and reproduce the state of this
并重现此状态
observable collection so there's a kind
可观察的集合，所以有一种
of interesting connection between those
那些之间有趣的联系
two and and another way to look at Rx is
第二，另一种查看Rx的方法是
to say why use a database when you have
说出为什么要使用数据库
a log and the log represents the
一个日志，该日志代表
presence and the database represents the
存在和数据库表示
past and the future is what mutates and
过去和未来会发生变化，
the present
现在
okay now and let's look at some concrete
好吧，现在让我们看一些具体的
streams here for example a clock the
流在这里，例如时钟
clock is aged a observable stream and in
时钟老化了可观察的流
rx there's a way to create a clock which
RX有一种创建时钟的方法
says in those first delay for 0 seconds
说在第一次延迟0秒
and then tick every one second and then
然后每隔一秒钟滴答一声，然后
what you see here is that you get this
你在这里看到的是你得到了这个
stream that will produce a value every
每个都会产生价值的流
second and we can do crazy things like
第二，我们可以做疯狂的事情，例如
computed prime numbers or only kind of
计算素数或仅
you know filtering out seconds that are
你知道过滤掉秒
prime numbers with this little code
这个小代码的质数
where we start with the timer and then
我们从计时器开始，然后
we filter out all the numbers that are
我们过滤掉所有的数字
not prime when it's a number and prime
当是数字和素数时不是素数
when its factors are only one and so it
当它的因素只有一个，所以它
only be divided by one by itself how do
只被一个人分开怎么办
we find the collection of factors well
我们发现因素的收集很好
they're using iterable so here you see a
他们使用的是可迭代的，所以在这里您会看到一个
pattern that appears a lot where you
出现在您很多地方的模式
combine both observables and intervals
结合可观察和间隔
in the same program now of course this
现在在同一程序中
program is not a program that you would
程序不是您想要的程序
kind of use in practice but it's just to
在实践中使用，但这只是为了
illustrate that the two intervals and
说明两个间隔和
observables often are used in the same
观测值经常用于同一
code okay good
代码还可以
back to our games so as I said these
回到我们的游戏，正如我所说的
games react on streams and then update
游戏在流上做出反应，然后更新
the screen and and in particular both of
屏幕，尤其是两个
them react on the keyboard so the book
他们在键盘上做出反应，所以这本书
game reacts on the on the spacebar ever
游戏在空格键上做出反应
I hit the spacebar the book jumps and um
我按了空格键，这本书跳了起来，嗯
the snake reacts whenever I can hit the
只要我能打蛇，蛇就会做出反应
up left or down key and then it's it's
向上或向下键，然后是
going to moved around and the graph now
要四处走动，现在该图
how do you convert events like the
您如何转换类似
keyboard event to observable collections
键盘事件到可观察的集合
so that is kind of
所以有点
and that our one operation that's super
而且我们的一项操作超级好
important because you have to go from
重要，因为您必须从
this world of events into the world of
这个事件的世界变成了
observables and here's the Fernet so I
可观察到的，这是Fernet，所以我
want to define an observable collection
想要定义一个可观察的集合
and observables 3 sorry I should not say
和Observables 3对不起，我不应该说
observable collection because the
可观察的集合，因为
observable collections are the other
可观察的集合是另一个
collection so it's an observable stream
集合，这是一个可观察的流
of key events and how do I do that well
关键事件，以及我该如何做好
I create new event handler and here I'm
我创建新的事件处理程序，在这里
using a kind of little an implicit
使用一种有点隐式
transformation because in Java you have
转换，因为在Java中
negative when you have a functional
当你有功能时
interface you can use the longer
界面可以使用更长
expression you have to do a little bit
表达你必须要做的一点
of magic but anyway I can define here my
魔术，但无论如何我可以在这里定义我的
event enter and now I add an event
输入事件，现在我添加一个事件
handler for each creepy press to my java
每个令人毛骨悚然的新闻处理程序到我的java
vaccine and the way that works is that
疫苗及其工作方式是
whenever the event handler is called it
每当事件处理程序被调用时
will notify the observer here of the key
会将钥匙通知给观察者
press so it will call on next on this
按下，它将在此上调用下一步
observe so here you see this is the
观察，所以在这里您看到这是
bridge between the world of events where
事件世界之间的桥梁
you have an event handler that this
你有一个事件处理程序
fault and the only thing this event
错误和唯一的事件
handler does is notify observer here
处理程序所做的是在此处通知观察者
that an event has happened and then I
发生了一件事情，然后我
unsubscribe I need to remove the event
取消订阅我需要删除活动
enter so this is a few lines of code to
输入，所以这是几行代码
to go from old fashioned event handlers
摆脱老式的事件处理程序
to observable streams and now you see if
到可观察的流，现在您看是否
I want to have only the space bar and
我只想要空格键和
events well it's still an observable of
事件很好，它仍然是可观察的
key events but I think all P process and
关键事件，但我认为所有P流程和
then I just used in this bulk operation
然后我只是在这个批量操作中使用
filter to just give me only the space
过滤器只给我空间
bar events so here you see I just write
酒吧活动，所以在这里你看到我只是写
a little bit of glue code and from there
一点胶水代码，然后从那里
on all my UI events have become
在我所有的UI事件上，
observable streams
可观察的流
now let's write a little bit of code to
现在让我们写一些代码来
get going with our game so what I want
开始玩我们的游戏，所以我想要
to do is I want to show the key events
我要做的是显示关键事件
here so if I press an a a press an aid
在这里，所以如果我按AA按一个援助
and I pray should be do I want to come
我祈祷我应该来
it out and show the key events in a
并在其中显示关键事件
graph like this and you can see already
这样的图形，您已经可以看到
that this is how the snake game is going
这就是蛇游戏的发展趋势
to work and here's the code so what do I
工作，这是代码，那我该怎么办
do
做
well there's a little bit of of binding
好吧，有一点点约束力
here to and to the UI so don't worry
在这里和用户界面之间，所以不用担心
that this is the line here that's shown
这是这里显示的行
on the chart and there's my keyboard and
在图表上，还有我的键盘和
now what I say is whenever you press a
现在我的意思是每当您按下
key
键
give me the text so this now an
给我文本，所以现在
observable of string here again ut then
再次在这里观察到字符串
I'm using bulk operations on observable
我正在可观察的批量操作
strings and what I do here is I want to
字符串，我在这里要做的是
whenever a key is hit I want to put it
每当按键时，我都想放它
on the graph so I have to kind of pair
在图上，所以我必须配对
it up with the index so this is the
它与索引，所以这是
first keystroke the second keystrokes of
第一次击键，第二次击键
each keystroke is paired with its index
每个按键都与其索引配对
and then I can graph it like this so how
然后我可以像这样绘制它
do i pair something with an index well
我是否可以将某些东西与索引很好地配对
there's an operator zip with index that
有一个带有索引的运算符zip
takes a observable stirring and add
进行观察并搅拌
pairs it up with it with a number and
将其与数字配对
the thing is that it gives the number as
问题是它给出的数字为
the second value of the pair so I have
这对的第二个值，所以我有
to do a map with a swap so here you see
进行交换地图，所以您在这里看到
in a few lines all the bulk operations
在几行中，所有批量操作
on these observables streams and then
在这些可观测的流上，然后
what I can do is I just subscribe to
我能做的就是我只订阅
this string whenever it fires I add that
每当启动时，我添加该字符串
pair to my chart and the chart will show
配对到我的图表，图表将显示
now here's a slightly different way to
现在这是一种稍微不同的方式
do that is I'm using this concept of
就是我正在使用这个概念
observable collections that I showed you
我给你看的可观察的收藏
so I create an observable collection and
所以我创建了一个可观察的集合
and then whenever and the disco tis the
然后在任何时候和迪斯科舞厅
same now whenever
现在一样
a keystroke happens with an index I just
击键发生在我刚刚创建的索引上
add this air to the observable list here
将此空气添加到此处的可观察列表中
and and so now I have the same picture
所以现在我有相同的图片
that I had I have an observable
我有一个可以观察到的
collection and I mutate and whenever
收集，我随时随地变异
something happens it will fire an event
发生某事会触发一个事件
at me and and this is the structure of
在我身上，这就是
all the game that we are going to that
我们要去的所有游戏
we have is we have an observable
我们有一个我们可以观察到的
collection that we're going to mutate
我们将要变异的集合
we're observing the changes we're
我们正在观察我们正在发生的变化
computing an answer and then we're going
计算一个答案，然后我们要去
to mutate the observable collection and
改变可观察的集合并
then we bind that observable collection
然后我们绑定那个可观察的集合
at the UI and another way to look at
在用户界面和另一种查看方式
this is this is the view this is the
这是这个观点，这是
model and this is the controller so it's
模型，这是控制器，所以
like whatever name you want to give to
喜欢你想给的名字
it and but really the interesting part
它，但真正有趣的部分
of the code is in here you observe
的代码在这里您观察
changes and then you can you know you
变化，然后你就能知道你
can you know you generate and state
你能知道你产生并陈述
mutations of on the model that you are
您所模型的突变
kind of you're dealing with and then how
那种你正在处理，然后如何
you want to bind it to the UI is really
您想要将其绑定到UI确实
not much of our concern there's like
我们关心的不是很多
again as I said in JavaScript in
就像我在JavaScript中所说的那样
particular there's millions of libraries
特别是有数百万个图书馆
that deal with this site here and but
在这里处理这个网站，但是
what we're going to do is we're going to
我们要做的是
focus on that site and here's another
专注于那个网站，这是另一个
example say that I want to simple and
例子说我想简单和
the key because in the first example I
关键，因为在第一个示例中
just whenever I hit the key I would show
每当我按下琴键就显示
it but I'm not always typing so I just
它，但我并不总是打字，所以我只是
want to kind of only whenever a key is
希望仅在按键是
hit I want to kind of sample it and then
打我想采样一下，然后
the next key is hit I want to kind of
下一个键是我想要的
continue with that let's look at the
继续，让我们看看
code here so we create a clock and then
代码在这里，所以我们创建一个时钟，然后
we say given the keyboard whenever and a
我们说只要有键盘就可以
keystroke happens we pair of the key
击键发生，我们对钥匙
with the value of the clock now this guy
现在的时钟值这个家伙
wasn't observed but we map and this one
没有被观察到，但是我们在地图上绘制了一个
here is in surplus
这是多余的
the result here is an observable of
结果是可以观察到的
observables and what we do if we switch
可观察物以及我们切换时的操作
between these streams whenever a new
在每一个新流之间
piece stroke happens so here you see in
发生中风，所以您在这里看到
the very little space is a quite
很小的空间是一个相当
complicated and code that for each
复杂并为每个代码
keystroke pairs it with the clock ticks
按键将其与时钟刻度配对
give nested three and switches to the
给嵌套三个并切换到
most recent string whenever he broke
他摔断时最新的弦
keyboard and event happens and then we
键盘和事件发生，然后我们
subscribe to this now this code has a
立即订阅此代码
book and I don't know if you have
书，我不知道你是否有
already seen it but if I am run this
已经看过了，但是如果我运行这个
code the result will be this and so what
代码的结果将是这个，等等
you see is that every time I hit a new
你看到的是，每次我打新
key time starts with zero and also I
关键时间从零开始，我也
want to show you this switch thing here
想在这里给你看这个开关
so what it does is it takes a stream of
所以它要做的是
streams and it's flattens into a new
流，它变平成一个新的
stream where it only takes the most
流最多的地方
recent value so if this one is now the
最近值，因此如果现在是
current thing as soon as a new stream
全新的流媒体
starts and for nothing the current
开始，没有电流
stream I'm switching to the next one
流，我要切换到下一个
as soon as in stream appears here I'm
只要流中出现在这里，我就是
switching to that think of this you know
切换到这个，你知道
as as us as a geek whenever new gadgets
和我们一样，只要有新玩意儿
happens I'm going to want that whenever
碰巧我会在任何时候想要
new gadget appears I want that so then
新的小工具出现了，我想要那样，然后
you know it always follows the latest
你知道它总是跟随最新的
gadgets now this problem here is that
小工具，现在这个问题是
you know and time doesn't seem to march
你知道，时间似乎没有前进
forward we're going to mapping here with
向前，我们将在这里映射
the clock but it needs to be that the
时钟，但必须是
clock starts at zero every time that's
时钟每次都从零开始
what we see here so the problem is that
我们在这里看到的问题是
whenever we map over the clock under
每当我们全天候在地图下方
this lambda birth in some sense we
从某种意义上说，这种λ出生
subscribe to the clock every time and
每次都订阅时钟，
that starts at time zero so what we have
从零开始的时间，所以我们有
to do is we have to take this clock and
要做的是我们必须采取这个时钟
we have to you
我们有你
is only one subscription to the school
只是学校的一个订阅
so that's kind of what we do here it is
所以这就是我们在这里所做的
publish this publish gives it a copy of
发布此发布为其提供了副本
the talk where we can use it as many
我们可以在哪里使用它的讨论
times as we want
我们想要的时代
we'll only subscribe to it once here so
我们在这里只订阅一次
you see that there's a very subtle
你会发现有一个非常微妙的
difference here is that I'm passing in
区别在于我要传递
this clock here via the publish and and
此时钟通过发布和
when we run that code you see that it
当我们运行该代码时，您会看到它
works as expected
按预期工作
and what you see in particular looks
以及您所看到的特别的外观
that if don't type for a while the clock
如果一段时间不输入
is still ticking so this is the first
还在滴答作响，所以这是第一个
time I had a keystroke at after seven
七点以后我有一次按键
seconds and then you see also see here
秒，然后你也看到这里
that when I made the screenshots that
当我制作截图时
the clock keeps going and and let me
时钟一直在走，让我
kind of look at the time so we were kind
看着时间，所以我们很友善
of running out of time so I'm going to
没时间了，所以我要
kind of skip this virtual time here and
有点在这里跳过这个虚拟时间，
but the main thing here is that what I
但主要的是我
want that that a clock is a so-called
希望时钟是所谓的
cult observable so that's kind of it
邪教可观察到的
I'll go to our our and and our IDE here
我将在这里转到我们的以及我们的IDE
so let's say I want to define and clock
所以说我想定义和计时
equals so here is our an hour clock
等于所以这是我们的一个小时时钟
which is observed of lon and what I'm
lon和我所观察到的
going to do is I'm going to subscribe to
我要做的就是订阅
it twice so I'm saying clock dot
它两次，所以我说的是时钟点
subscribe and then you know X arrow
订阅，然后您知道X箭头
print line to subscribe see clock once
打印行以订阅，请查看时钟一次
and now I'm going to subscribe to the
现在我要订阅
clock a second time but I'm going to and
再次计时，但我要去
I'm going to wait to set all right so
我将等待一切​​就绪
here what you see is I'm going to
在这里，你看到的是我要去
subscribe to the clock twice and and and
两次订阅时钟，然后和
and to print them and at the same time
并同时打印
now what you will see is that this
现在您将看到的是
subscription to the clock and this
订阅时钟和这个
subscription to the clock both will have
订阅时钟都将有
this will get their own ticks so this
这将得到他们自己的滴答声，所以这
one got it 0 then I sleep then I
一个得到它0然后我睡觉然后我
subscribe to the clock and that one will
订阅时钟，那个将
kind of start again at 0 so let's run
再次从0开始，让我们开始吧
this guy and see if that works there we
这个家伙，看看是否可行，我们
go
走
so indeed there's now two ticking
所以确实有两只公鸡在滴答作响
each independently they're both picking
每个人都都在摘
independently and and what that is in
独立地以及那是什么
our xpeke is that this clock is it's
我们的xpeke是这个时钟是
cold that's what we're saying it's like
这就是我们所说的寒冷
every subscription gets a new clock if I
每个订阅都会得到一个新时钟，如果我
want to and make this clock hot what I
想让这个时钟变热
can do is I can publish it and then what
可以做的是我可以发布它，然后
I do here is I can connect to it so I
我在这里是因为我可以连接到它，所以我
say clock connect and I should remove
说时钟连接，我应该删除
this guy here so now what happens is
这个人在这里，所以现在发生的是
there to this clock is publisher it
这个时钟在那里是发布者
means that there's only one subscription
表示只有一个订阅
everybody that subscribes to this block
订阅此区块的所有人
will share the underlying subscription
将共享基础订阅
to this and you know the clock will only
为此，您知道时钟只会
you will only kind of start subscribing
您只会开始订阅
to the other side when you call connect
通话时转到另一边
so in this case I connect immediately I
所以在这种情况下，我会立即连接
subscribe a wait and I subscribe and now
订阅等待，我订阅，现在
what you will see is that there's only
您会看到的是，只有
one clock that is shared so just keep
共享一个时钟，所以保持
this in mind you see there's two
请记住，有两个
different clocks but now if you see this
不同的时钟，但现在如果您看到这个
one oh now the other one and you see
一个哦，现在另一个，你看到了
that they do and subscriptions share the
他们所做的和订阅共享
same value for the clock so that is how
时钟的值相同，所以
you kind of move between cold and hot
你在冷热之间移动
observables let's go back to our slides
可观察的东西让我们回到幻灯片
and and let's go and look at at our gain
让我们去看看我们的收益
and because you know this is all about
而且因为你知道这一切都是关于
playing the game and we now have enough
玩游戏，我们现在有足够的
and general knowledge to gonna do and
和一般知识要做
assembled a man but as I said the game
集合了一个男人，但是正如我所说的
is super simple and and we have now seen
非常简单，我们现在已经看到
all the operators necessary to build the
所有需要的运营商
game today
今天的比赛
this is really the information in the
这确实是
game it's kind of a cheat but all games
游戏有点作弊，但所有游戏
work like that
这样工作
and what happens that and when you think
发生了什么，当您想到
that this book is moving it's really not
这本书在动，真的不是
poke that's moving the box stays at the
戳移动框保持在
same place it's the grass that's moving
在同一地方，它在移动的草地
so if you look here is that this piece
所以如果你看这边
of grass a few clock ticks later is this
几钟滴答的草是这个
piece of grass and a few o'clock diction
一块草和几点钟
in there it's there so it's the grass
在那儿，那是草
that moved from left to right and the
从左向右移动
book stays in place so how do we code
本书留在原处，那么我们如何编码
that well we create old tiles here again
好了，我们再次在这里创建旧瓷砖
we're using the bulk operations on
我们正在使用批量操作
intervals to create a list of tiles and
创建图块列表的间隔和
and what we're going to do then is we're
然后我们要做的是
going to say well the and the clock
要说的很好，并且时钟
moves with a speed of three and ticks
以三点速度移动
per second so every and everything the
每秒，所以每一件事
grass moves three and pixels to the left
草向左移动三个像素
that's going to know what doing here and
那会知道在这里做什么
and as I said here's like no this is a
就像我说的那样，这不是
prime man is not here he would and turn
总理不在这里，他会转身
over in his grave if he would be in his
如果他会在他的坟墓里结束
grave and because we're doing very poor
严重，因为我们做得很差
man's ticks so we're just saying you
男人的滴答声，所以我们只是在说你
know we take the velocity and we're
知道我们以速度，而我们
calculating the next velocity and we do
计算下一个速度，我们做
that with the scan operator we start
与扫描操作员一起开始
with zero and then every time the clock
零，然后每次时钟
ticks we have to populate the new
滴答声，我们必须填充新
velocity of the grass well in this case
在这种情况下，草的速度很好
the grass constant velocity so just kind
草恒速，所以好
of you're copying the the previous
您正在复制前一个
velocity to be the next velocity and
速度是下一个速度
then we subscribe and as we said just
然后我们订阅，正如我们所说的
now know that this is the distance that
现在知道这就是距离
we have to move the grass and then we
我们必须移动草，然后我们
update here the model to move the grass
在此处更新模型以移动草
and then of course the grass has to end
然后当然要结束草
and turn around
然后转身
to appear the other side so this is like
出现在另一边，所以就像
though how you make the grass moves it's
虽然你是如何让草移动的
really just one line of code and right
真的只是一行代码而已
here the scanned operator works like
在这里，扫描的运算符的工作方式就像
this it takes an operator and whenever
这需要操作员，每当
it takes a stream and it converts the
它需要一个流，并转换
stream by plying repeatedly applying
通过反复申请流
that operator so in this case it starts
该运算符，因此在这种情况下它开始
with the first element and then it
与第一个元素，然后
combines these two into this and it
结合这两个到它
combines Erick it combines these two
结合埃里克，它结合了这两个
into this then it combines these two
然后结合这两个
into this etc etc so that's why you see
进入这个等等等等，这就是为什么你看到
here it takes the initial velocity this
这需要初始速度
is the next value in the stream and it
是流中的下一个值，它是
combines so this is the next value of
结合起来，所以这是下一个值
the tree it combines them to that
把它们结合在一起的树
calculate the next one now here's how we
现在计算下一个
make the book jump so if we want to make
让书跳起来，所以如果我们想
the book jump it its velocity is
这本书跳起来的速度是
changing because you saw that the book
变化，因为你看到这本书
went up and then went down so we start
上升，然后下降，所以我们开始
with an initial velocity and average at
初始速度和平均值为
every clock tick we subtract the gravity
每个时钟滴答声，我们减去重力
and then insert the boat first goes up
然后先把船插上去
and then it goes down so here again you
然后它下降了，所以再次在这里
see you recognize the scan because V is
看到您识别出扫描，因为V是
determined into VI minus one etc so you
确定为VI减一，以此类推
see here the the next velocity is based
看到这里，下一个速度是基于
on the previous velocity and etc so here
在以前的速度上等等
you see the code and for the book so
您会看到代码和这本书，因此
let's look at first here is it starts
让我们先来看这里
with you know some initial velocity and
你知道一些初始速度
then the next velocity is the previous
那么下一个速度就是上一个
velocity - gravity so that's what you
速度-重力就是你的意思
see here so the next velocity is the
看到这里，所以下一个速度是
previous velocity minus the gravity so
以前的速度减去重力，所以
here you see this is the computation of
在这里，您会看到这是
the position of the book but now we make
书的位置，但现在我们做
the book jump whenever you
每当你这本书跳
the spacebar happens so whenever the
空格键会发生，因此无论何时
spacebar happened we get so the base bar
空格键发生了，我们得到了
is a stream of velocities and then
是一连串的速度，然后
whenever that happens we calculate and
每当发生这种情况，我们都会计算并
the trajectory of the bark and then we
树皮的轨迹，然后我们
can when the next job happens we kind of
下一次工作发生时，我们可以
stop listening to this one and then we
停止听这个，然后我们
just update the position to here you see
只需将位置更新到此处即可
the jump of the book is just four lines
这本书的跳跃只有四行
like this so whenever a jump happens we
这样，所以每当发生跳跃时，我们
take an initial velocity given by the
取由
jump then we just compute this
跳，那么我们就算这个
trajectory and we when we update the
轨迹，当我们更新
bark position when you update a model we
您更新模型时的树皮位置
will ignore any values that are when the
将忽略当
book is below earth and and then we'll
书在地下，然后我们将
stop listening to this thing whenever a
每当有
new jump appears okay so preventing
新的跳转似乎还可以，因此可以防止
falling through the floor is done in the
从地板上掉下来是在
in that piece of code okay and here's it
在那段代码中，好的，这就是
take until so it takes two streams and
直到直到需要两个流
it's just down the the second stream
就在第二流
whenever something happens on the first
每当第一件事发生
string so here's a stream of positions
字符串，所以这里是职位流
of the bug we shut it down whenever the
的错误，每当
next jump appears now how do we what do
现在出现下一跳我们该怎么办
we do with the spacebar well the
我们用空格键做得很好
spacebar the bug jumps with speed eight
空格键，错误以八速跳跃
and we say whenever you know we hit the
我们说只要您知道我们就击中了
spacebar and we ignore the spacebar when
空格键，当我们忽略空格键时
Burke is in the air and then we play a
伯克在空中，然后我们玩
sound if that's not the case and then we
声音，如果不是这样，那么我们
can you know we make the jump so this is
你能知道我们跳了吗，这是
again how you wire up the spacebar to
再次将空格键连接到
making the Burke jump and let's look at
让伯克跳起来，让我们看看
that in the actual code and where's our
在实际代码中，我们在哪里
bug here's our game
bug，这是我们的游戏
so here you see grass and and here you
所以在这里你看到草，在这里你
see that that quote exactly the code
看到那个报价准确的代码
that I showed you for the jumps whenever
我向你展示了跳跃的机会
the jump happens we're recomputing a guy
跳跃发生了，我们正在重新计算一个家伙
here's the spacebar Cotto evite and run
这是空格键Cotto调用并运行
this game and to run it so this is the
这个游戏并运行它，所以这是
behavior so whenever I hit the spacebar
行为，所以每当我按下空格键
but when I hit the spacebar on the
但是当我按下空格键
button there nothing happened so I hope
按钮没有任何反应，所以我希望
you can hear that I hit the spacebar
你可以听到我按下空格键
nothing happens only when the dark is in
只有在黑暗中什么也不会发生
the air so now the next question is for
空气，所以现在下一个问题是
how do we determine this the defection
我们如何确定这种背叛
our rental car hits the Sun okay over
我们的租车可以打太阳了
here the bug does give you some here it
这个错误确实在这里给你一些东西
hits the Sun so how do you do that well
射中太阳，所以你怎么做得好
that's also quite simple code let's go
那也是非常简单的代码，让我们开始吧
and score dance and and for for that we
跳舞，为此，我们
look at a spreadsheet and how it does
看一下电子表格及其功能
that if you look at a spreadsheet when
如果您查看电子表格，
you have a formula here so the formula
你这里有一个公式，所以公式
is a1 plus b1 now that that means the
是a1加b1现在这意味着
value of this cell changes whenever one
每当一个
of these cells change so that what you
这些细胞的变化，所以你
see here when I go and change the a two
看到这里，当我去改变一个两个
to eight then automatically the value of
到八，然后自动将
C goes from 7 to 13 hello the the result
C从7变为13你好结果
of this cell is whenever the input cell
每当输入单元格时，此单元格的
changes it will change well in our X we
变化，它将在我们X中发生很好的变化
have an operator for that too so it
也有一个运算符
makes a stream of changes here and a
在这里进行一系列更改，
stream of changes here and whenever one
在这里以及任何时候发生的变化
of the things changes we recompute the
事物的变化我们重新计算
output so this operator here is exactly
输出，所以这里的这个运算符就是
stolen from spreadsheets so here the
从电子表格中被盗，所以这里
input cells this is the output cells
输入单元格，这是输出单元格
whenever input 1
每当输入1
of the input cell changes we recompute
重新计算输入单元格的变化
the output cell and and there there are
输出单元格，那里有
ivories that hook up rx to excel
将RX连接到Excel的象牙
actually and again it works the same as
实际上，它一次又一次地与
these observable collections or Excel
这些可观察的集合或Excel
well is the observable collection and
好是可观察的集合
whenever a change happens it will fire
每当发生变化时，它将触发
an adjacent notification and then we can
相邻的通知，然后我们可以
hook it up and then cell works like this
挂上它，然后细胞像这样工作
combined latest operator okay so how
结合了最新的运算符好吧，怎么
does that code look like well we take
该代码看起来是否很好，我们接受了
the position of the bug as an observable
错误的位置可观察
stream so that gives us the x and y
流，使我们得到x和y
coordinates plus the bounding box so
坐标加上边框
that's what we see here so we look at
这就是我们在这里看到的，所以我们来看
the flight of bug that's a observable
可以观察到的错误飞行
stream of X Y and width and height and
XY，宽度和高度以及
the thing for the Sun so the Sun is also
太阳的东西，所以太阳也是
an observable dream of XY plus there and
可观察到的XY加梦
within the height and then what we do is
在高度范围内，然后我们要做的是
we use this combined latest so every
我们使用最新的组合，所以每个
time either of these and change we check
时间这些和改变我们检查
whether the two collide and the
两者是否发生碰撞，
collision just really look whether these
碰撞只是真的看这些
things over also in this case they
在这种情况下，事情也结束了
collide and so here we see and there's
碰撞，所以在这里我们看到了
the Sun there's the block and here is
太阳在那里有障碍，这是
you know the collision so red means they
你知道碰撞是红色的
don't collide a green means that they do
不要碰撞绿色意味着他们
commit but what we want is we want to
承诺，但我们想要的是我们想要的
kind of you know detect well when they
你们知道他们什么时候能很好地发现
when we have to change the Sun to a
当我们必须将太阳改变为
heart and back so really we're not
心和背部，所以我们真的不是
interested in the collisions we're
对我们感兴趣的碰撞
interested in the the X detection so we
对X检测感兴趣，所以我们
want to know when something goes from
想知道什么时候发生
non-commissioned to collision and we
不负责碰撞，我们
want to know when it goes from collision
想知道它何时从碰撞中消失
to null collision so here's how we do
消除碰撞，这就是我们的方法
that we use this adding buffer to one
我们使用这个添加缓冲区到一个
where we combine these
我们结合这些
is in portions of two like this and then
在两个这样的部分中，然后
we just check whether the first is
我们只是检查第一个是
different from the second and then we
与第二个不同，然后我们
know when to change from art to some
知道何时从艺术转变为某些
okay so just to prove that I'm not
好吧，只是为了证明我不是
joking with you and here is exactly that
和你开玩笑，这就是
code so there and there's the combat
代码，所以就在那里战斗
latest with the bounding box I check
我最新的边界框
whether they intersect and I kind of
他们是否相交，我有点
bind them in pairs of two and I check
将它们成对绑定两个，我检查
whether it changes from collision to non
是否从碰撞变为非
collation and and then you know if it
整理，然后您知道是否
changes from if it was a collision I
从如果是碰撞我改变
showed the heart if it goes back to non
表现出心脏，如果它回到非
coefficient I show the Sun again and I
系数我再次显示太阳
play the little music okay so here you
播放一点音乐好吧，在这里你
see this again I mean the imports are
再看一次，我的意思是进口
longer than the actual code and its
比实际的代码及其
really simple codes good and this is the
非常简单的代码很好，这是
other operator that I use here this is
我在这里使用的其他运算符是
the uplink buffer so what it does is it
上行链路缓冲区，那么它是做什么的
takes you know it breaks up a stream in
让您知道它会破坏流
in in fragments like so and but as I
像这样，但像我一样
said the code is really very short and
说代码真的很短，
simple and nearly as short or are the
简单且几乎一样短
list of imports it's nearly as long as
进口清单几乎与
the code which proves that really in the
该代码证明了
end we are just plumbers only we plumb
结束，我们只是水管工，只有我们垂手
with codes instead of with gonna pipes
用代码代替管道
and if you want to have an you want to
如果你想拥有一个
have for information about RX RX is
有关于RX的信息RX是
available in many languages and Java
提供多种语言和Java版本
JavaScript C++ dotnet Objective C and
JavaScript C ++ dotnet目标C和
dark streams are
黑暗的溪流是
to our X and and then both Dale has also
到我们的X，然后Dale也
kind of a nice example of our ex using
这是我们前任使用的一个很好的例子
games and her pictures are works
游戏和她的照片都是作品
prettier she uses the magic ponies and
更漂亮的她使用魔法小马和
so on where I use boxed simple box and
所以在哪里我使用盒装的简单盒子
snake and so yeah I think I'm a little
蛇，所以是的，我想我有点
bit over time so but I hope that there's
随着时间的流逝，所以我希望
still people that are there that want to
还有那些想要
ask questions
问问题
oh yeah I come to this quote there's a
哦，是的，我来引用这句话
few questions if you don't mind
几个问题，如果你不介意
answering the first note I'm sorry that
回答第一个音符，对不起
I kind of went over all right we're fine
我有点没事了，我们很好
with that
接着就，随即
though there is a some of them are a
虽然有一些是
little bit out of context but one of
有点脱离上下文，但其中之一
them is called observable and non
他们被称为可观察的和非
discrete event generator and okay so
离散事件生成器，好吧
actually let me say this there's no a
实际上让我说这没有
bad question so I love a freshman so
不好的问题，所以我爱一个新生
this one is interesting so let me kind
这个很有趣所以让我好一点
of go back to my code here and and what
回到我的代码在这里，以及什么
you see here and then I can I can
你看这里，然后我可以
explain it so what this guy does this
解释一下，这个家伙是做什么的
publish it turned a Colt observer ball
发布它变成了柯尔特观察球
into a hot observable so the cold versus
可以观察到热
what has nothing to do with discrete and
与离散和无关
versus non discrete and in some sense in
与非离散的比较
in rx there's only discrete things so
在RX中只有离散的东西，所以
they're the the notion of time is
他们是时间的概念是
discrete so and the the events fire and
如此离散，事件触发并
so there's no continuous anything and is
所以没有连续的东西
a yeah there there is like there's a
是的，那里就像有一个
very special version of the replay
重播非常特别的版本
subject that remembers the last value
记住最后一个值的主题
and so you know that that is yeah that
所以你知道那是的
is I would say the closest that comes to
我会说最接近
a kind of you know no discrete event
一种你不知道离散事件
stream but it's really still debris
流，但实际上仍然是碎片
because you know the only thing it
因为你知道唯一的一件事
really does is it remembers the last
真的是，它记得最后一个
value
值
okay one other question which is hanging
好吧，另一个悬而未决的问题
from some time it's a renowned
一段时间以来，它是著名的
observable collections ask you if they
可观察的收藏询问您是否
are ready to use on Java or are they
准备在Java上使用还是
just plan for the future okay let's go
为未来做计划好吧，走吧
here because I didn't show a snake yet
在这里，因为我还没有表现出蛇
but if you look at the snake and let me
但是如果你看着蛇让我
make it a little bit smaller and then
将其缩小一点，然后
it's going to fit on the screen so what
它会适合在屏幕上，所以
you see here is that here's the snake
你看这里是蛇
here you see snake model so while the
在这里，您会看到蛇模型，
snake model is it's an observable
蛇形是可观察的
collection an observable list and this
收集一个可观察的清单
data number number is really a pair of
数据号号码真的是一对
numbers it's like no and in in Scala I
数字就像没有，在Scala中
could really make it into kind of a pair
真的可以变成一对
of number number and but this observable
的数量，但是这个可观察到
thing is really there right it's not
事情真的在那里，不是
something that it's there and what I do
那里有什么，我做什么
here and B come on there's a little bit
这里和B来一点
of space so so here I create this is the
空间，所以在这里我创建的是
model so that's the observable
模型，这是可观察的
collection and then here I bind it to
集合，然后在这里将其绑定到
the view so I to say on the line chart
视图，所以我要在折线图上说
just add that model so this binding it
只需添加该模型，然后将其绑定
to the view I don't have to do anything
认为我不需要做任何事情
and then what they do here if I say
然后我说他们在这里做什么
converts the model to an observable
将模型转换为可观察的
collection and I only want to kind of
收藏，我只想种
listen for things that were added so in
聆听添加的内容
this case because for the snake game I
这种情况是因为对于蛇游戏我
want to I need to know and when
想知道我什么时候
something is added and then so so this
添加一些东西，然后这样
gives me an observable and an observable
给我一个可观察的和可观察的
stream of the list of the positions of
职位列表流
the snake parts okay so you see here now
蛇分开了，所以你现在在这里看到
very clearly that there's the model
很清楚，有模型
which is this observable collection I
这是我可观察的集合
bind it to the interview which is in
将其绑定到正在进行的采访中
this case a line chart which I don't
这种情况下我不折线图
think
认为
anybody ever thought that you could use
任何人都认为您可以使用
a line chart to implement the snake and
折线图，以实现蛇和
then the snake here and I should use the
然后这条蛇，我应该用
very handy IntelliJ feature here to add
非常方便的IntelliJ功能在这里添加
the type is the the the snake here is
类型是这里的蛇
now an observable stream of a list of
现在可观察到的
the positions of the snake okay
蛇的位置还可以
and there's like a little bit of
还有一点点
boilerplate here but you see I derive it
这里的样板，但你看到我得到它
directly from the snake model and and
直接从蛇模型和
then the rest what let's say here so
那么其余的我们在这里说
this is kind of what happens here's like
这就是这里发生的事情
you know you see I'm listening to the
你知道你看到我在听
keyboard here and it goes up and down
键盘在这里，它上下
and then you see that in here I'm
然后你看到我在这里
updating the model so this really
更新模型，所以这真的
follows the picture that I show it where
跟随我在哪里展示的图片
you know there's the model there's the
你知道那里有模型
view and I kind of update the model
查看，我有点更新模型
based on the events that I get and out
根据我进出的事件
of the changes and I all right yes I
的变化，我可以，是的，我
would say that that you know it's
会说你知道这是
observable collections you know this is
可观察的集合，你知道这是
nothing to do with rx right these are in
与RX无关，这些都在
the Java SDK they are in the.net SDK and
.NET SDK中的Java SDK和
there is something let me go to my
有件事让我去我的
slides if you are in the dotnet world
如果您在互联网世界中，请滑动
and there is the reactive UI and and
还有反应式用户界面和
this is all based around the kind of
这全都基于
demo based observable collection so it's
基于演示的可观察集合，因此
going to be or what I showed you here
或我在这里展示给你的东西
but Paul and does this guy this is kind
保罗，这家伙好吗
of a real framework that that then they
一个真正的框架，然后他们
use it up amongst others to kind of you
用它来和你一样
do the same thing and it's really about
做同样的事情，这实际上是关于
and the this combination of observable
和可观察到的这种结合
collections and observable streams
集合和可观察流
so I think it's so my answer the short
所以我想这就是我的简短回答
answer is yes I think they are real and
答案是可以的，我认为它们是真实的，
and many frameworks have done and and
许多框架已经完成，并且
but the thing to keep in mind is that
但要记住的是
they're complementary to rx OD the
它们是对RX OD的补充
observable collections are the the
可观察的集合是
actual collections that you can mutate
您可以变异的实际集合
then you can observe their changes and
然后您可以观察他们的变化，
those changes you process with rx and
您使用rx处理的那些更改和
then you can feed them back as new
然后您可以将它们作为新的
mutations to the observable connections
可观察连接的突变
and that's how you get this cycle and
这就是你得到这个周期的方式，
that makes you that makes your code take
这使你使你的代码
okay great question I I think that's it
好，很好的问题，我认为就是这样
the other ones we we can follow up I
其他我们可以跟进的我
think we can wrap up now so the there is
认为我们现在可以总结一下，所以
some just some questions in regard to
一些关于一些问题
links and that which will be providing
链接以及将提供的链接
so all right let me just steal the
好吧，让我偷
screen from you a second all right yeah
从你的屏幕第二秒钟好吧
so we just yeah
所以我们只是
there is in addition to first of all
首先有
Eric thank you very very very much for
埃里克非常非常感谢你
the presentation and I know we ran
演示文稿，我知道我们参加了
overboard a little bit so I hope you
有点过分，所以我希望你
didn't mind too much but it was really
不太介意，但确实
great and it's more than like you know
太好了，远不止您想像的
the people I should don't mind they are
我不介意的人
pretty much pretty much everyone hung
几乎所有人都挂了
out so I'm almost very much interested
出去，所以我几乎非常感兴趣
so just a couple of notes the are
因此，只需注意几个
reactive extensions on Twitter is a good
Twitter上的反应式扩展是一个很好的选择
account to follow the RX other Doc's
帐户以跟随RX其他文档的
while they are Java API they're very
虽然它们是Java API，但它们非常
very good I think a good dogs to teach
很好，我认为可以教好狗
you about reactive extensions and Eric's
关于反应式扩展和Eric的内容
site applied duality calm and I think
网站应用对偶冷静，我认为
that once we provide recording which
一旦我们提供记录
will be on youtube.com slash their
将在youtube.com上将其
brains TV will also follow up with a
大脑电视也将跟进
blog post with the links these links and
博客文章以及这些链接和
the ones that Eric sent with the source
埃里克（Eric）与来源一起发送的
code etc so Eric once again thank you so
代码等，所以Eric再次感谢您
much and thank you everyone for
非常感谢大家
attending and hope to see you next time
参加并希望下次见
all right bye bye bye bye
再见再见再见